Guide to the Hartt School Community Division records ARCH058
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt School Community Division records
1936-2018
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt School. Community Division
ARCH058
5.13 Linear Feet (19 containers)
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Existence and Location of Copies
Some of the materials in this collection, primarily photographs, have been digitized and are available at: http://mdid3.hartford.edu/explore/explore/?c=allcollections:67). Access is limited to the University of Hartford Campus.
Historical Note
The Hartt School, under various names, has always served both traditionally-aged college students and members of the larger Greater Hartford Community. The Community Division has a reputation for providing high quality musical education for both children and adults. Today's Community Division was formerly called the Julius Hartt School of Music and the "Non-Collegiate School of Music."
Scope and Contents
The collection contains minutes, brochures, concert programs, photographs, accreditation/self-study reports, and other material documenting the Hartt School Community Division.
Arrangement
The collection is currently arranged into five series with two additional accessions which have not yet been fully processed and merged into the collection. The series are: I. Marketing Materials, 1962-2018; II. Subject Files, 1936-2013; III. Photographs, 1953-1976; IV. Recordings, 2015; V. Duplicates.
Music Instruction and study; Photographs; Dance Study and teaching; Public relations; Hartt School. Community Division; University of Hartford; Hartt School; Hartt College of Music; Hartford Ballet; School of the Hartford Ballet; Dance Connecticut
- Marketing Materials, 1962-2018; I
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of marketing materials including, brochures, pamphlets, programs and other public relations materials used to promote the Hartt School Community Division from 1962-2018, with the bulk of the materials from 2001-2018. Also included are oversized posters and two buttons.
  - 1962-1963 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 1)
  - 1969 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 2)
  - 1975 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 3)
  - circa 2000-circa 2007 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 4)
  - circa 2000- circa 2012 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 5)
  - 2001-2002 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 6)
  - 2002-2003 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 7)
  - 2003-2004 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 8)
  - 2004 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 9)
  - 2004-2005 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 10)
  - 2005 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 11)
  - 2005-2006 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 12)
  - 2006 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 13)
  - 2006-2007 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 14)
  - 2007 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 15)
  - 2007-2008 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 16)
  - 2008 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 17)
  - 2008-2009 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 18)
  - 2009 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 19)
  - 2009-2010 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 20)
  - 2010 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 21)
  - 2010-2011 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 22)
  - circa 2011-2012 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 23)
  - 2011 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 24)
  - 2011-2012 (Box Marketing Materials 1, Folder 25)
  - 2011-2012 (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 1)
  - 2012 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 2)
  - 2012 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 3)
  - 2012-2013 (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 4)
  - 2013 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 5)
  - 2013-2014 (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 6, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
  - 2014 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 7, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
  - 2014-2015 (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 8, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
  - 2014-2015 (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 9)
  - 2014-2015 (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 10)
  - 2015 Summer (Box Marketing Materials 2, Folder 11, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
  - 2015 Oct - 2018 Jun, 2018-07-11-01
    - Nutcracker, 2015 Oct - 2016 Jan (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 1-2, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
    - The Compass/ Alumni, 2015 Oct (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 3)
    - Donor Booklet, 2015 Oct (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 4)
    - Gift Of Dance, 2015 Oct- 2015 Nov (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Give The Gift Of Music, 2015 Nov (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 7)
    - Save The Date Alumni Weekend, 2015 Nov (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 8)
    - FSTS Dance Mag. Ad, 2015 Nov (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 9)
    - Summer MTI + Jr., 2015 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 10)
    - Library Flyers, 2015 Dec- 2016 (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 11)
    - Marketing, 2016-2017 (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 12)
    - Generic Summer Ad, 2016 Jan (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 13)
    - Summer Master Classes, 2016 Jan (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 14)
    - Hartt Works, 2016 Feb (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 15, Box Shared CD Box 1)
    - CT Parent, 2016 Feb - 2016 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 16-17)
    - March Suzuki Workshop, 2016 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 18)
    - Trombone Day With Jim Nova, 2016 Mar - 2016 Apr (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 19)
    - Suzuki Senior, 2016 Apr (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 20)
    - CT Alliance For The Arts Education, 2016 Apr (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 21)
    - African-American Affairs Commission Awards Gala, 2016 Apr- 2016 May (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 22)
    - CT Parent, 2016 Apr- 2016 May (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 23)
    - Percussion With Sheets, 2016 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 24)
    - The Red Shoes, 2016 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 25, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
    - Valley Press, 2016 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 26)
    - Simsbury Class Mailer, 2016 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 27)
    - The Red Shoes, 2016 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 28)
    - Audition Day, 2016 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 29)
    - Meet The Masters, 2016 Jun-Jul (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 30)
    - Hartt Works, 2016 Jun-Jul (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 31)
    - FSTS Brosters, 2016 Jun-Jul (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 32)
    - FFA Posters, 2016 Jul (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 33)
    - FSTS Ballet, 2016 Jul (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 34)
    - Suzuki Institute and Teacher Workshops, 2016 Jul-Aug (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 35)
    - Fall Open House, 2016 Aug (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 36)
    - Open Auditions For The Nutcracker, 2016 Sep (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 37)
    - Dance, 2016 Oct (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 38)
    - The Nutcracker, 2016 Oct-Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 39, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
    - Practice-A-Thon, 2016 Nov-Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 40)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 2016 Nov- 2017 Jan (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 41)
    - FSTS Brochures, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 42)
    - Holiday News-Nut, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 43-44)
    - SMTI NAFME, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 45)
    - Nut PS Handouts, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 46)
    - First Steps in Music, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 47)
    - HCD's Second Annual Alumni Weekend, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 48)
    - Nutcracker at Hartt School, 2016 Dec (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 49)
    - Library Flyers, 2017 Jan (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 50)
    - Spring-Summer 2017 Performance calendar, 2017 Feb-May (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 51)
    - CCC Push 2017, 2017 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 52)
    - Northeast Horn Workshop, 2017 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 53)
    - March Suzuki 2017, 2017 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 54)
    - Simsbury COFC Invite '17, 2017 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 55)
    - Northeast Horn Workshop, 2017 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 56)
    - SMTI/Michelle Fiertek Article in HTFD Mag, 2017 Mar (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 57)
    - Hartt Works, 2017 Mar (Box Shared Small Oversized 2)
    - Rockville HS Musical, 2017 Apr (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 58)
    - Audition Fest, 2017 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 59, Box Shared Small Oversized 1, Folder acc. 2017-09-14-01)
    - Margaret H. Ashford Scholarship, 2017 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 60)
    - Spring Fest 2017 (Dance), 2017 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 61)
    - Hartt Suzuki 2017, 2017 Jul-Aug (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 62)
    - Adult Dance Class Voucher, 2017 Sep-2018 Jun (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 63)
    - Marketing, 2018 (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 64)
    - Marketing, Undated (circa 2014-2018) (Box Marketing Materials 3, Folder 65)
    - Marketing, circa 2015-2017; 2 Pieces buttons, duplicates (Box Artifacts Box 12, Object acc. 2017-09-14-01)
      File Plan
      Consists of two buttons which read "I danced at Hartt today"
      Cultural artifacts
- Subject Files, 1936-2013; II; 0.83 Linear Feet (2 containers)
  - Ambrose, Priscilla "Penny", 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Catalogs, 1950 - circa 2012; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
  - Commencement, 1968; 1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Dance, Circa 1960-1971; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Director's Report and Hart Line, 1971-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1951-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Faculty Manuals, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Financial Overview and Satellite Proposal, 1984 Mar 16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - George, Mark, 2007 Aug 9 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Greater Hartford Community Chorus, 1964-1976, undated; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
  - Guzulescu, Meg, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Hartt School Training Orchestra and Greater Hartford Youth Orchestra, 1939-1995; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Pellettieri, Louis J., 1941 - 1946; 1987; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Performances, 1936-2012\; Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Satellite Studios, 1937, undated; Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1953-1976; III
  - Ambrose, Priscilla ('Penny"), Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Dance, circa 1960-circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Greater Hartford Community Chorus, 1968-1975, undated; Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Greater Hartford Youth Orchestra Romania Tour, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Greater Hartford Youth Orchestra Switzerland Tour, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hartt School Training Orchestra and Greater Hartford Youth Orchestra, 1953-1960, circa 1976, Undated; circa 1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Pellettieri, Louis, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Recordings, 2015; IV
  - Taking Care of the Children: Celebrating the Life, Work, and Legacy of Dr. Watson Wilbur Morrison, 2015; 2 Compact Discs DVD, duplicates (Box Shared CD Box 3)
- Duplicates, V (Box 2, Folder 17)
  This series consists of duplicate copies of materials from the collection, primarily marketing materials.
- Acc. 2016-03-02-01 (Dance), 3.83 Linear Feet (9 containers)
  - Accreditation, Self-Studies, and Reports
    - NASD Approval Letters, 1976-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Joint Commission on Dance and Theater Accreditation, 1979; 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
    - NASD HEADS Report Forms, 1983-2008 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - NASD HEADS Data Summaries, 1984-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - NASD Self-Study Report, 1987; 1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 10, Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Certificate Program in Performance Preparation, Circa 1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - NASD Briefings, 1990 Apr - 1997 Dec, undated (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
    - NASD Annual Questionnaires and Correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - NASD Progress Reports, 1994-2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    - NASD Audits and Commission Action Reports, Circa 1997; 2001-2006 (Box 2, Folder 11, Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ballet and School
    - 25th Anniversary Clara Reunion, 1963-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 25th Anniversary, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - BFA Proposal, 1986-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
    - Brochures, 1988; 1992; 2002 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Fire Exits and Fire Marshall, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Open Focus for Dancers / Imagery, 1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - School of the Hartford Ballet, Enyd Lynn / Dance CT Syllabus, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Technique D Syllabus, 1996-2010, undated (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Dance CT Certificate Teaching Program, 1997-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 2, Box Shared CD Box 1)
    - Dance a Story, 1999-2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Class Orientations, 2000-2004, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - DPCY, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Expectations, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Forms and Printed Ephemera, 2002, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Budget Background, 2003-2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Summer Intensive, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Faculty, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Pre-Ballet Division Syllabus, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - School of Dance CT Syllabus, Susan Brooker, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Photographs
    - Prints
      - 25th Anniversary (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
      - 25th Anniversary Clara Reunion, 1963-1986 (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
      - Contact Prints, 1997 Dec - 1999 Mar 24, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-11)
      - Faculty Photographs, 1998, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Governor Rowland, Circa 2003 Nov 26 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Hartford Ballet Photos, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Nan Melville, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Nutcracker [?] "Lotta", undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Peter O'Brien, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Rosalie O'Connor, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Rock Hard, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Sets and Props, undated (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
      - Studio Candids (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Summer Intensive Program, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Unidentified Child Performers, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Unidentified Class, 2002 Jul 22, undated (Box 6, Folder 24-26)
      - Unidentified Performers, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Negatives, Transparencies, and Slides
      - Richard Bergen, undated (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
      - Break, undated (Box 7, Case 1)
      - Cross Roads, 1999 (Box 7, Case 1)
      - Fall 2000 (Pom, Nut, Fresh) (Box 7, Case 1)
      - Tom Giroir, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Kids, undated (Box 7, Case 2)
      - Jennifer Lester, undated (Box 7, Case 2-3)
      - F. Marchese, undated (Box 7, Case 4)
      - MOD, undated (Box 7, Case 4)
      - Nutcracker, 1998 (Box 7, Case 4)
      - Reinin', 1994, undated (Box 7, Case 4)
      - Pascal Rioult, undated (Box 7, Case 4)
      - Slides for Inside / Nut, undated (Box 7, Case 4)
      - Sport, undated (Box 7, Case 5)
      - Tap Jazz, undated (Box 7, Case 5)
      - Transparencies, undated (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
      - Untitled, 1997 Jul (Box 7, Case 5)
      - Untitled, 2001 Jul 12 (Box 7, Case 5)
      - Untitled, 2001 Jul 19 (Box 7, Case 5)
      - Unidentified Slides, undated (Box 7, Case 5-6)
      - Unidentified Negatives, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Wardrobe Negatives, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Viamarez BFA Slides, undated (Box 7, Case 6)
    - Compact Discs (CDs) and Floppy Disks (Box Shared CD Box 1)
  - Artifacts (Box 8)
    This series consists of a plaque and two wardrobe trunks filled with costumes, primarily from the Nutcracker.
- 2016-11-01-02 - Hartford Ballet, School of Hartford Ballet, and Dance CT Photographs, Circa 1990 - 2002; Acc. 2016-11-01-02; .17 Linear Feet (1 container) (Box 1)